A new game begins
Spiral: From the Book of Saw is a horror, mystery
film directed by Darren Lynn Bousman.
Working in the shadow of an esteemed police veteran, brash Detective Ezekiel “Zeke” Banks and his rookie partner take
charge of a grisly investigation into murders that are eerily reminiscent of the city’s gruesome past.
Unwittingly entrapped in a deepening mystery, Zeke finds
himself at the center of the killer’s morbid game.
Detective Zeke Banks, played by Chris Rock.
Marcus Banks, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Detective William Schenk, played by Max Minghella.
Captain Angie Garza, played by Marisol Nichols.
Detective Marv 'Boz' Bozwick, played by Dan Petronijevic.
Detective Fitch, played by Richard Zeppieri.
Spiral: From the Book of Saw is a 2021 American horror thriller film  directed by
Darren Lynn Bousman and written by Josh Stolberg and Peter Goldfinger.
It serves as a spin-off from and the ninth installment of the Saw film series.
The film stars Chris Rock, Max Minghella, Marisol Nichols, and Samuel L.
Jackson, and follows police efforts to stop a Jigsaw copycat killer.
The original creators of the series, James Wan and Leigh Whannell, as well as Rock
and series veteran Kevin Greutert, serve as executive producers.
Talks of another Saw installment began after the release of Jigsaw
(2017), with Rock wanting to branch out into the horror genre.
The project was officially announced in May 2019, with Rock
polishing a script by Stolberg and Goldfinger.
The rest of the cast joined in July, with filming taking
place in Toronto through that month and August.
Scheduled to be released in May 2020, Spiral was delayed due to the COVID-19 pandemic, and was
theatrically released in the United States on May 14, 2021, by Lionsgate Films.
The film grossed a total of $40.6 million against a budget of $20 million, becoming the lowest
grossing installment in the franchise, and received mixed reviews from critics.
A tenth installment, Saw X, was released in September 2023.
The film explores themes of sequel, murder, police
corruption, survival horror, body count.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and mind_bending.